<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_tana-franko.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Continuous Annoyment: Bringing More Zen to a Hectic Writing Environment</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2016/continuous-annoyment-bringing-more-zen-to-a-hectic-writing-environment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tana Franko</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-22:write-the-docs-2016/continuous-annoyment-bringing-more-zen-to-a-hectic-writing-environment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tana Franko
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbztc/"&gt;http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbztc/&lt;/a&gt;
The hectic pace of documentarian tasks is only accelerating these days, spurred on by things like continuous deployment and tools that enable a new, higher level of collaboration. These changes bring not only unprecedented opportunities but also unprecedented challenges.
Today&amp;amp;#39;s technical communicators need to adapt to cope with this change. In this talk, Tina the Tech Writer is back, now leading a team of writers. The team has been almost too successful at proving the value of documentation. Facing a mountain of urgent requests for documentation coverage, potential writer burnout, and attrition, she puts her hedgehog brain skills to practical application on a plan to bring the team to new levels of engagement, happiness, and value -- all while learning to say no when appropriate. It&amp;amp;#39;s all about balance. Tina will share results from her team&amp;amp;#39;s experiment, while outlining a way you can design your own plan to balance any set of challenges and opportunities you&amp;amp;#39;re facing.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>